elgato.com 2019-01-05

# Data Protection | elgato.com

## Privacy Policy

We thank you for your interest in our website. Protecting your personal data is very important for us. The following text informs you in detail about how we handle and protect your data.

### 1\. Access data and hosting

You may visit our website without revealing any personal information. With every visit on the website, the web server stores automatically only a so-called server log file which contains e.g. the name of the requested file, your IP address, the date and time of the request, the volume of data transferred and the requesting provider (access data), and documents the request. These access data are analysed exclusively for the purpose of ensuring the smooth operation of the website and improving our offer. This serves according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit f GDPR the protection of our legitimate interests in the proper presentation of our offer that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. All access data are deleted no later than seven days after the end of your visit on our website.

###  Third-party hosting services 

Data are also processed by a third-party provider that we have engaged to render hosting and website presentation services on our behalf. This provider processes on its servers all data that are collected in the manner specified below when you visit our website or fill in forms made available for this purpose in our online shop. Data are processed on other servers only in the scope described herein.  
This service provider is based in the USA and is certified to the EU-US Privacy Shield. The current certificate can be looked up [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). Based on this agreement between the USA and the European Commission, the latter has recognised entities certified to the Privacy Shield as those ensuring an adequate level of data protection.

### 2\. Data collection and use for processing the contract

We collect personal data that you disclose to us whenever you place an order or contact us (e.g. via contact form or by email). Mandatory fields are marked as such because we absolutely need those data to perform the contract or process your contact request, and you would otherwise not be able to complete your order or send the contact request. It is evident in each input form what data are collected. We use the data that you disclose to us to perform the contract and process your enquiries according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit b GDPR. Upon contract completion, any further processing of your data will be restricted, and your data will be deleted upon expiry of any retention period applicable under relevant statutory regulations, unless you expressly consent to the further use of your data or we reserve the right to further use your data in the scope and manner permitted by law, of which we inform you in this notice.

### 3\. Transfer of data

We disclose your data to the shipping company in the scope required for the delivery of the ordered goods according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit. b GDPR. Depending on the payment service provider you have selected during the ordering process, we disclose the payment details collected for order processing purposes to the bank commissioned to handle the payment and, as the case may be, to the payment service provider commissioned by us or to the selected payment service. Some of those data are collected by the selected payment service providers themselves if you open an account with them. In such a case, during the ordering process, you must register with your payment service provider using your access data. In this respect, the privacy notice of the relevant payment service provider applies.

We use the services of a payment provider, which has its registered office outside the EU. Personal data are disclosed to that company only to the extent required to perform the contract.

Disclosure of data to a shipping provider If, when or after placing your order, you have given your express consent to us doing so, we disclose your e-mail address and phone number to the selected shipping provider based on that consent according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit. a GDPR, in order to enable the shipping provider to contact you to advise you of the delivery or agree with you the delivery details. You may revoke your consent at any time by sending a message to the contact option described below or by directly notifying the shipping provider at the contact address specified below. After you revoke your consent, we will delete the data disclosed for this purpose, unless you expressly consent to the further use of your data or we reserve the right to further use your personal data in the scope and manner permitted by the law, of which we inform you in this notice. 

Reinsch Fulfillment GmbH , Am Donauhafen,  4 94315 Straubing, Germany

### 4\. Email newsletter

E-mail advertising if you subscribe to the newsletter 

If you subscribe to our newsletter, we will regularly send you our e-mail newsletter based on your consent according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit a GDPR, using the data required or disclosed by you separately for this purpose.

You may unsubscribe from the newsletter service at any time. For this purpose you can either send a message to the contact option specified below or use the opt-out link in the newsletter. Upon unsubscription, we will delete your email address unless you have expressly consented to the further use of your data or we reserve the right to further use your personal data in the scope and manner permitted by the law, of which we inform you in this notice.  
The newsletter is sent to you by our service provider Mailchimp (The Rocket Science Group LLC, 675 Ponce de Leon Ave, NE Suite 5000 Atlanta, GA 30308 USA) who processes data on our behalf and to whom we disclose your email address.

This service provider is based in the USA and is certified to the EU-US Privacy Shield. The current certificate can be looked up [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). Based on this agreement between the USA and the European Commission, the latter has recognised entities certified to the Privacy Shield as those ensuring an adequate level of data protection.

### 5\. Integration of the Trusted Shops Trustbadge

We have integrated the Trusted Shops Trustbadge on this website in order to display our Trusted Shops Trustmark and offer the Trusted Shops membership to customers after placing an order.

This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimal marketing of our offer according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit f GDPR that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. The Trustbadge and the advertised trust badge services are offered by Trusted Shops GmbH, Subbelrather Str. 15C, 50823 Cologne, Germany. With every use of the Trustbadge, the web server automatically saves a so-called server log file which contains e.g. your IP address, the date and time of the request, the volume of data transferred and the requesting provider (access data), and documents the request. Those access data are not analysed and are automatically overwritten no later than seven days after the end of your website visit. Other personal data are transferred to Trusted Shops only if you decide to use or have already registered to use Trusted Shops products after placing an order. In such a case, the contract concluded between you and Trusted Shops applies. 

### 6\. Cookies and web-analysis

To improve the user experience on our website and enable you to use its certain features in order to show suitable products or conduct market research, some pages of this website use the so-called cookies. This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimised presentation of our offer according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit a GDPR that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. A cookie is a small text file which is stored automatically on your end device. Some of the cookies we use are deleted after you close the browser session, i.e. when you close the browser (that’s the so-called session cookies). Other cookies are stored in your end-user device and enable us to recognise your browser when you visit us again (persistent cookies). To check the cookie storage period, you can use the Overview function in the cookie settings of your web browser. You can configure your browser for it to inform you whenever a page uses cookies and decide on a case-by-case basis whether to accept or reject the cookies on a given website or generally. Every browser has a different policy for managing the cookie settings. The browser’s policy is described in the Help menu of every browser and explains how you can change your cookie settings. To find out how to change the settings in your browser, see the links below:  
Internet Explorer™: [https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies ](https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)  
Safari™: [https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=de_DE&viewlocale=en_US ](https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411?locale=de_DE&viewlocale=en_US)  
Chrome™: [https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&hlrm=en](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&hlrm=en)  
Firefox™: [https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences ](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences%20https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)  
Opera™ : <http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.20/en/cookies.html>

Please note that disabling cookies may limit your access to some features of our website.  

### Using of Google (Universal) Analytics for web analytics

For the purpose of website analytics, this website uses Google (Universal) Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC (www.google.com). This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimised presentation of our offer according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit f GDPR that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. Google (Universal) Analytics uses methods, like e.g. cookies, that enable an analysis of your use of the website. The information collected automatically by cookies about your use of this website are as a rule transmitted to and stored on a Google server in the United States. At the same time, as IP anonymisation is enabled on this website, the IP address will be shortened before being transmitted within the area of member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases, the full IP address will be sent to a Google server in the USA and shortened there. Generally, Google does not associate the anonymised IP address, transmitted from your browser through Google Analytics, with any other data held by Google. Google LLC is headquartered in the USA and is certified to the EU-US-Privacy Shield. You will see the up-to-date certificate [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list). Based on this agreement between the USA and the European Commission, the latter has recognised entities certified to the Privacy Shield as those ensuring an adequate level of data protection.

You may prevent the data generated by cookies and related to your use of the website (incl. your IP address) from being recorded and processed by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available through the following link: [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

As an alternative to this browser plugin, you may click on this link to prevent future collection of data by Google Analytics on this website in the future. In this process, an opt-out cookie will be stored on your end-user device. If you clear your cookies, you will have to click the link again. 

### 7\. Social media plugins

**Youtube video plugins**

We have embedded third-party content on our website. This content is made available by Google LLC ("Provider"). Youtube is operated by Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA (”Google”). In respect of Youtube videos which are embedded in our website, we have enabled the privacy enhanced mode. This means that Youtube does not collect or store information about visitors unless they play the video. Embedding the video serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimal marketing of our website according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit f GDPR that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests To find out more about the purpose and scope of collection, further processing and use of the data by the Providers, and to learn about your rights in this respect and how you can customise your browser to better protect your privacy, please see the data privacy policies of Google.

### 8\. Sending rating reminders by email 

Rating reminder by Trusted Shops If, when or after placing your order, you have given us your express consent to doing so according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit a GDPR, we will disclose your e-mail address to Trusted Shops GmbH, Subbelrather Str. 15c, 50823 Cologne, Germany (www.trustedshops.com), so that they can email you a rating reminder. You may revoke your consent at any time by sending a message to the contact option specified below or directly to Trusted Shops.

### 9\. Contact possibilities and your rights

You are entitled to be obtain free-of-charge information concerning data stored about your person and, as the case may be, to correct, restrict the processing, enable the portability of, or delete those data. If you have any questions about how we collect, process or use your personal data, want to enquire about, correct, block or delete your data, or withdraw any consents you have given, or opt-out of any particular data use, please contact us directly using the contact data provided in our site notice. You may also submit a complaint to the responsible data protection supervisory authority.

### Right to object

If we process personal data as described above to protect our legitimate interests that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests, you may object to such data processing with future effect. If your data are processed for direct marketing purposes, you may exercise this right at any time as described above. If your data are processed for other purposes, you have the right to object only on grounds relating to your particular situation. After you have exercised your right to object, we will no longer process your personal data for such purposes unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims. This does not apply to the processing of personal data for direct marketing purposes. In such a case we will no longer process your personal data for such purposes.
